早上好  医生
Morning, doc!
早上好  肯尼
Good morning, Kenny.
兄弟  你的电缆断了
Brosef, your cable's out.
我没用电缆
I don't have cable.
我用的数字天线
I have a digital antenna.
为什么
Why?
数字天线的画面和音效都更胜一筹
Digital antennae receive superior picture and sound quality,
电视台都不要钱
and the channels are free.
对  但那样只能收到十个台
Yeah, but you get, like, 10 channels that way.
我只看三个台
I only watch three.
能让我从你的电视上搭根线吗
You mind if I run a line to your tube?
有线电视的人下周才给我开通信号
Cable guy can't fit me in till next week.
能看十个台总比没台好
Come on, 10 channels are better than none.
确实
Yes, they are.
好了
All right.
谢了  朋友
Gracias, amigo.
不客气
No hay na que agradecer.
什么
What?
科利医生走后  雷兹尼克医生就没人带了
Dr. Reznick was orphaned once Dr. Coyle was transferred,
她会加入我们的团队
so she'll be joining our team.
你好  我是克莱尔
Hi. I'm Claire.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
你就是有自闭症的那位
Are you the autistic one?
不
No.
是我
That's me.
肖恩·莫菲医生
Dr. Shaun Murphy.
我们手上有两个很简单的病例
We've got two pretty straightforward cases,
积极的团队就该公平竞争
nice level playing field for an eager group.
没兴趣
Not interested.
竞争能促进团队合作
Competition can foster teamwork,
而团队合作有助于
which can lead to a greater understanding
更好地摸清和评估住院医师的优缺点
and appreciation of residents' strengths and weaknesses
提高病患治疗水平
and improve patient care.
我们在实习时  格拉斯曼用过同样的招数
You're playing the same game Glassman had us do when we were interns.
没兴趣
Not interested.
获胜的队伍优先协助
Winning team gets first dibs
下周所有的手术
on assisting on all surgeries next week.
-同意  -同意
- In. - In.
拒绝
Out.
我选天才小子
I pick the boy genius.
是你
That's you.
布朗医生
Dr. Browne.
卡卢
Kalu.
雷兹尼克医生
Dr. Reznick.
谢谢  我很期待
Thank you. I'm looking forward to it.
谢谢
Thank you.
跟上次一样的筹码
Same stakes as last time?
当然
Absolutely.
奎因
Hi, Quinn.
听说你肚子疼
We hear you've had some stomach pain.
我们可以检查一下吗
Do you mind if we take a look?
没那么疼
It doesn't hurt that bad.
小家伙一直说没事
Poor thing says everything is okay,
奎妮今天说不想去游泳
but when Quinnie didn't want to go swimming today,
我就知道肯定出问题了
I knew that something must be wrong.
我们会尽量轻一点
We'll be as gentle with her as possible.
奎因的父母出远门了
Quinn's parents are out of town,
所以临时叫我来照看
so I'm -- I flew in to babysit.
好
Okay.
我看看
Let's see.
-那是  -阴茎
- That's a... - Penis.
她不是女孩
She's not a girl.
他是个男孩
He's a boy.
良     医
第一季    第十四集
只是一时的
It's just a phase.
别那么说
Stop saying that.
我不是男孩  我是女孩
I'm not a boy. I'm a girl.
-你是跨性别者  -对
- You're transgender? - Yes.
不
No.
奎因有跟我和杰瑞德一样的XY染色体
Quinn has XY chromosomes like Jared and me,
不是你的XX染色体
not XX like you.
科学上来说他是男性
Science says he's male.
不  奎因有性別不安症
No, Quinn has gender dysphoria.
她认知的性别跟实际性别不符
Her assigned gender is not the one she identifies with.
是不匹配  莫菲医生
She's mismatched, Dr. Murphy.
但生物学上...
But biologically --
撇开生物学
Other than biologically,
你怎么知道自己应该是男孩
how do you know - you're supposed to be a boy?
你的问题说不通
Your question doesn't make sense.
我不是应该是什么
I'm not supposed to be anything.
我就是男孩
I am a boy.
生物学规定的
Biologically, that's it.
好  麦氏点有深压痛
Okay, deep tenderness at McBurney's point.
可能是急性阑尾炎
Could be acute appendicitis.
莫菲  做影像学检查确认
Murphy, get imaging to confirm.
肖先生  病历显示你在上课时晕倒了
Mr. Shaw, your chart says that you passed out in class.
-你教什么  -历史
- What do you teach? - History.
我没吃早饭  所以有点晕
I got a little dizzy because I skipped breakfast.
没事
I-it's nothing.
学校坚持要叫救护车
The school insisted on calling an ambulance.
最近几个月有吃什么药吗
Taken any medications in the last few months?
六周前背突然很痛
Uh, I took some Vicodin
我就吃了点维柯丁[止痛药]
after I threw out my back six weeks ago,
之后又得了肠胃感冒  就吃了氧氟沙星
and then I had a stomach flu, so I took Ofloxacin.
但感冒没全治好
But the flu part didn't totally go away,
又吃了阿奇霉素和强的松
so I took Azithromycin and Prednisone
因为腺体肿了
because my glands were swollen.
但我的喉咙还很痛  所以吃了环丙沙星
But I still had a sore throat, so I took some Cipro.
哪个医生给你开的这些药
What doctor prescribed you all that?
都是我药柜里剩下的
Uh, they were leftovers I had in my medicine cabinet.
好  请躺下
All right, lay back for me.
我是带着双胞胎的单身父亲
Look, I'm a single dad with twins
他们会把在学校接触到的可怕细菌带回家里
who bring home every disgusting germ they touch at preschool.
我不上班就没收入
I can't afford to miss work.
你发烧了  还输过两次液
You've got a fever and you've gone through two IVs
所以我判断你严重脱水了
which tells me that you're severely dehydrated.
我摸你的胃部时  你会有绞痛感
You can't stand me touching your stomach without wincing in pain.
雷兹尼克医生  给肖先生做超声波
Dr. Reznick, let's get Mr. Shaw here an ultrasound.
-我们试了一段时间  -五个月
- We've been trying for while. - Five months.
我的最佳排卵期是二十年前
I realize my prime egg days were two decades ago,
但我一直很注意
but I've been vigilant.
试过排卵试纸  促黄体生成素和促卵泡激素测试
Ovulation kits, LH and FSH testing,
基础体温
basal body temp.
也检查过雌二醇和抗穆勒氏荷尔蒙水平
I've checked my estradiol and AMH levels.
传统方法没用
The old-fashioned way wasn't working.
好  有很多种可能
Okay, well, there are a lot of possibilities to consider.
很多是良性的  很多容易治疗
Many benign, many easily corrected.
我会给你俩采个样
So I will take some samples from you both,
做测试  到时再说
run some tests, we go from there.
时间紧迫
There's a clock.
我们想知道如果做人工授精或试管受精
We need to know - if we start with IUI or IVF...
你们俩不用担心
Both of you -- you need to stop worrying.
伊莎贝尔  你不是第一个来这问这些的
Isabel, you are not the first 40-something woman
四十几岁的女人
to come here and ask these questions.
我也如此
Myself included.
你们来找我  是因为相信我吧
You came to me - because you trust me, yes?
对  按照我的程序来
Right. So let me do what I do,
你们专注彼此就行
and you two focus on each other.
我们有彼此  宝贝
We're a team, babe.
共同面对  好吗
In this together, all right?
好
Okay.
霍华德  你的阑尾恐怕已经破裂了
I'm afraid, Howard, your appendix has already ruptured.
立刻安排手术室  呼叫梅伦德斯
Book an OR stat and page Melendez.
等等  我得想想谁来照顾我的孩子
Wait. I need to figure out who's gonna take care of my kids,
还要通知学校找人给我代课
call the school so they can get subs for my classes.
肖先生  如果现在不做手术
Mr. Shaw, if we don't get you into surgery now,
感染会扩散  你会感染性休克
your infection could spread and you could become septic.
布朗医生会打电话通知到相关人员
Dr. Browne will make all the necessary phone calls
我给你准备手术
while I prep you for surgery.
对吧  布朗医生
Isn't that so, Dr. Browne?
我们会照顾好你的  肖先生
You're in good hands, Mr. Shaw.
交给我们吧
We've got you covered.
走
Let's go.
你好
Hello.
你穿裙子吗
Do you wear dresses?
莫菲  闭嘴
Murphy, don't.
奎因是自认为是女孩的男孩
Quinn is a boy who thinks he's a girl.
我想知道他那样认为的原因
I want to know why he thinks that.
我有时穿裙子  有时穿紧身裤
Sometimes I wear dresses, but sometimes I wear leggings.
你喜欢粉色吗
Do you like the color pink?
我更喜欢紫色
I'm more of a purple girl.
-你玩娃娃吗  -从五岁起  我就超迷美人鱼
- Do you play with dolls? - Since I was 5, but I'm super into mermaids.
你上舞蹈...
Do you take dance --
用于练习推理和创造力的问话游戏
莫菲  到「二十问」了
Murphy, 20 questions are up.
我才问了四个
I only asked four.
-你喷香水吗  -无关紧要
- Do you wear perfume? - It doesn't matter.
CT准备好了  走吧
The CT's ready. Let's go.
-你总会涂指甲吗  -走吧
- Do you always paint your nails? - Let's go.
穿孔的阑尾取出来了
Perforated appendix is out.
清洗还是不清洗
Lavage or no lavage.
布朗医生
Dr. Browne.
伤口缝合前清洗
Lavage before closing the wound
会降低残余的积液
decreases residual fluid accumulation
-减少残余污染  -克莱尔说得对
- and minimizes residual contamination. - Claire's right.
但最近研究指出穿孔阑尾炎手术进行了冲洗
Although, a recent study documented a higher abscess rate
脓肿的几率会更高
when irrigation was used for perforated appendicitis.
有人做功课了
Well, someone did their homework.
自从《美国外科学》发表了我的论文后
I'm partial to AMSURG
我就很爱看了
since they published me.
以医学生的身份
As a medical student?
是关于经导管主动脉瓣置换手术
It was about the cost and stabilization of disease
主动脉瓣置换手术
in patients undergoing transcatheter
费用和稳定病情的论文
and surgical aortic valve replacement.
你想专门从事心胸外科吗
Are you thinking of specializing in cardio-thoracic?
女生总可以幻想一下吧
A girl can dream.
进行缝合吧
Staple up and close up.
其实
It's, uh --
你能加入我很开心  摩根
it's good to have you on board, Morgan.
能有另一位外科女医生真好
It's great to have another female surgeon.
对不起
I'm sorry,
我们做不成朋友
you and I are not gonna be friends,
一起出去玩  一起过夜
hanging out, having sleepovers,
互相编辫子
braiding each other's hair.
我其实并没有这个意思
That's not exactly - where I was going with it.
等实习期结束
When residency's over,
医院可能只会在我们中留下两人
the hospital's likely only keeping two of us.
肖恩有格拉斯曼的喜爱  他肯定进
Shaun is Glassman's pet project, so he's in.
杰瑞德不受欢迎  他肯定出局
Jared is persona non grata, so he's out.
这意味每次你胜利了我就会输
Which means every time you win, I lose.
反之亦然
And vice versa.
感谢提醒
Thanks for the heads up.
你认为他是复杂还是困惑呢
Do you think he's complicated or confused?
兄弟  别再称呼她为「他」
Dude, you've got to quit calling her a "He."
如果你不尊敬我们的病人
We're never going to win this competition
我们永远没法成功
with you disrespecting our patient.
-在怀俄明州没有变性人吗  -好吧
- Don't they have transgender people in Wyoming? - Okay.
治疗变性人
Transgender patient care
不在我上的医学院授课范围内
was not part of my - medical school curriculum.
你学过吗
Was it part of yours?
没有
No.
奎因没有阑尾炎
Quinn doesn't have appendicitis.
他有睾丸癌
He has testicular cancer.
她
She.
我们在奎因左侧睾丸上发现一个肿瘤
We found a mass on Quinn's left testicle.
她得了癌症  但是
She has cancer, but --
-我要死了吗  -不会
- Am I gonna die? - No, no.
预后情况很好
Prognosis is very good.
我们在它扩散前发现了它
We've caught it before it spread,
我们通过手术移除肿瘤
and we'll do surgery on the mass to remove it.
CT也显示出他骨质缺乏
The CT also showed he has osteopenia.
莫菲  不许再说「他」
Murphy, stop with the "He."
奎妮  是你妈妈
Quinnie, it's your mom.
我得去...
I -- I have to --
当然
Of course.
骨质缺乏
Osteopenia.
-指骨密度低是吗  -是的
- That's low bone density, right? - Yeah.
你怎么会知道
How'd you know that?
你知道我为什么会得癌症吗
Do you know how I got cancer?
有几个可能原因  但是我...
There are several - possible causes, but I --
-微石症腮腺炎尿道下裂  -莫菲
- Microlithiasis, mumps, hypospadias -- - Murphy.
上皮生殖细胞肿瘤
Intraepithelial germ cell neoplasia,
腹股沟疝  艾滋病
inguinal hernia, HIV --
莫菲  够了
Murphy. Enough.
你的父母马上就来了
Your parents are on their way here.
他们刚告诉我
Um, they just told me --
奎因你在服用发育阻断剂吗
Quinn, are you on puberty blockers?
这是骨质缺乏的可能原因
That's the likely cause of the osteopenia.
你在服用亮丙瑞林或组胺瑞林吗
Are you taking leuprorelin or histrelin?
我服用亮丙瑞林九个月了
I've been leuprorelin for nine months.
你怎么不早说
Why didn't you say anything earlier?
因为我父母不想让我奶奶知道
Because my parents didn't want my grandma to know.
看起来他有个脓肿
Looks like he has an abscess.
你被感染了
You have an infection.
我们会弄掉它  给你服用抗生素
We'll drain it, put you on antibiotics.
不用担心
It's nothing to worry about.
只是你得在医院
It just means - you might be in the hospital
多待几个晚上
a couple of extra nights.
我不能多待几个晚上
I -- I can't spend a couple of extra nights.
我得出去
I need to get out of here.
你是担心自己的孩子吗
Are you worried about your kids?
他们和我姐姐在一起  很安全
Well, they're with my sister, they're safe,
但他们从没离开过我一晚
but they've never spent a night without me
自从他们出生后
since they were born.
那把这次当作是赐福吧
Well, then consider this a blessing.
没有孩子  给自己放个假
A free vacation from your kids.
他们是我的生命
They're my life.
我妻子去年死于卵巢癌
My wife died of ovarian cancer last year.
我
I...
我讨厌医院
I hate hospitals.
真对不起
I'm so sorry.
不然我找个电脑过来
Why don't I find a laptop
你可以和孩子们视频
so you can Skype with them?
我再从小儿科弄几个玩具熊来
And I'll rustle up a couple of toy bears from Peds
给你带回家
for you to take home.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我得提醒你
I want to reassure you
发育阻断剂
that the puberty blockers
不会导致你的癌症
are in no way responsible for causing cancer.
亮丙瑞林确实导致了你的骨质缺乏
The leuprorelin did cause your osteopenia.
意思是我不能再服用发育阻断剂了吗
Does this mean I have to stop taking puberty blockers?
是的
Yes.
我们会给你膳食补充剂
We'll get you on dietary supplements
帮助增强你的骨质
to help regain your bone strength,
但是发育阻断剂在伤害你
but the puberty blockers are hurting you.
没有它们你会好起来的
You'll be fine without them.
会好的
Fine?
我不想要喉结
I -- I don't want an Adam's apple
低沉的嗓音和全身长毛
or a deep voice - or hair all over my body.
你们不能让这些再发生  对吧
You can't reverse that, can you?
恐怕不行
No, I'm afraid not.
女孩子也会有体毛
Girls have body hair, too.
玩具熊  和孩子视频
Toy bears, Skype with kids --
你很上道
you've got game.
「上道」
"Game"?
我相信我的所作所为
I believe the name for what I did
叫作「基本品格」
is "Basic human decency."
每个人都有目的
Everyone has an agenda.
有时是有意的  有时不是
Sometimes it's conscious, sometimes it's not,
但它一直存在
but it's always there.
而「仁慈之母」是你的常态
And you've got this whole "Queen of kindness" thing down pat.
这么年轻就如此愤世嫉俗
Awfully cynical for someone so young.
并不是愤世嫉俗
Mm, not cynical.
这只是世界运作的现实
Just the reality of how the world works.
是霍华德
It's Howard.
他突发高烧  40℃
He spiked a fever, temp's 105.
血压急速下降  80/40
BP's tanking, 80 over 40.
床单脏了
He's soiled his sheets.
伤口很干净  感染现在应该结束了
Site's clean. Infection should be clearing by now.
-怎么回事  -我不知道
- What's going on? - I don't know.
呼叫梅伦德斯
Page Melendez.
给我五百毫克的扑热息痛
Give me 500 milligrams acetaminophen,
两克美罗培南静脉注射
2 grams of meropenem IV infusion empirically.
做血液化验和全血细胞计数马上送去培养
Run a chem panel, CBC, and get cultures ASAP.
撑住  霍华德
Hang in there, Howard.
我们会弄明白的
We're gonna figure this out.
奎因·达比的化验出结果了吗
Any word on Quinn Darby's labs?
今天太忙了  我无能为力
Big backup today. Nothing much I can do.
好了给你发短信
Text you when they're ready.
好的
Yeah.
你好  格斯
Hey, Gus.
我今天在自助餐厅看见了树莓
I saw raspberry and rose petal doughnuts
加玫瑰花瓣甜甜圈
in the cafeteria today.
给你买了最后一份
Got you the last one.
你还记得
You remembered.
谢谢
Thank you.
霍华德·肖的化验结果
Howard Shaw's labs.
-我为你加急了化验  -你最好了
- I put a rush on them for you. - You're the best.
你为什么给格斯一个甜甜圈
Why did you give Gus a doughnut?
出于好意
I was being nice.
我急需病人的化验结果
I needed my patient's labs expedited.
-格斯喜欢甜甜圈  -你这是贿赂
- Gus likes doughnuts. - It's called bribery.
我这是「基本品格」
I call it "Basic human decency."
再见
See you later.
霍华德感染了超级病菌
Howard has a superbug.
艰难梭状芽胞杆菌感染
A C. Diff infection?
抗拒任何药物
It's resistant to all medication.
奎因的术前化验结果正常
Quinn's pre-op labs are normal,
明天一早我们就能做手术
so we can do the surgery first thing in the morning.
手术为腹股沟睾丸根治切除术
The procedure is called a radical inguinal orchiectomy.
能根治是因为生癌的睾丸会被整个移除
It's radical in that the entire cancerous testicle is removed.
功能性不会改变
All functionality will remain the same.
奎因一到两个礼拜后就能恢复正常活动
Quinn should be able to resume her normal activities in one or two weeks.
听见了吧宝贝  是好消息
See? Baby, that's good news.
并不是
No, not really.
失去了发育阻断剂
Without the puberty blockers,
我会成为芭蕾里一个有胡子的怪物
I'll be the freak in ballet with a mustache.
没有其他选择了吗
Aren't there any other options?
我希望有
I wish there were --
如果我们做双侧睾丸根治切除术
If we do a bilateral orchiectomy,
奎因会达到女性的睾酮水平
Quinn will have the testosterone level of a girl.
我们不会移除双侧睾丸
We are not removing both testicles.
你是要阉了我的孙子吗
You want to castrate my grandson?
不
No.
对于莫菲医生的言语我很抱歉
I'm so sorry - for Dr. Murphy's outburst.
反正我都会做性别确认手术
I'm gonna have gender confirmation surgery
等我十八岁
when I'm 18 anyway.
为什么不现在做
Why not just do it now.
奎因还是个孩子
Quinn is a child
还在玩换装和假扮游戏
who still plays dress-up and make-believe.
也许有天他会想要自己的孩子
He may want to have children of his own some day.
我们给你们点私人空间
We'll give you some privacy.
谢谢
Thank you.
我不允许你们
I will not allow you --
不是你来决定的
It's not up to you.
你现在让我很怀疑选你是否明智  莫菲
You are making me doubt the wisdom of drafting you, Murphy.
如果你随便对病人说煽动性的言语
If you go around saying inflammatory things to people,
只会让他们烦恼
it will only upset them.
我怎么知道自己说了煽动性语
How will I know if I said something inflammatory
如果我不说出口
until I say it?
先拿卡卢试试
Test it on Kalu first.
你们可以为这个病案准备共享决策援助的时候试试
Which you can do while the two of you prep an SDA for this case.
共享决策援助
An SDA?
A Shared Decision Aid
就是将这个艰难决策的正反面
is a paper presenting the pros and cons
-呈现... -我知道那是什么  莫菲
- of making a difficult -- I know what it is, Murphy.
但是为什么我要被惩罚
But why am I being punished?
这不是惩罚  这是必要的步骤
It's not a punishment, it's necessary.
能帮助奎因的家人
It'll help Quinn's family
明白在奎因的问题上他们所有可能的选择
understand all the options available to them for her care.
明白了吗
Understood?
明白了
Understood.
粪便培养和灵敏试验
The stool culture and sensitivity test
都表明你对所有抗生素都有耐药性
indicate that you're resistant to every antibiotic.
这只可能发生在你使用过
Which only happens when you've been exposed
所有抗生素的情况下
to every antibiotic.
我  是我自己造成的
I -- I did this to myself?
但是我以前服用这些药并没有问题
But I've used those medications before without a problem.
现在怎么出问题了
Why did this happen now?
你没有看医生
You weren't under a doctor's care,
所以你很有可能因为错误的症状
so you were likely taking the wrong medication
服用了错误的药物
for the wrong symptoms.
但是你们可以治好的  对吗
But you can fix this, right?
我们得做一个结肠造口术
We're gonna have to perform a colostomy
将造瘘袋系统连接到你的腹部
where we attach an ostomy pouching system to your abdomen
来收集你体内的排泄物
to collect waste from your body.
多久
For how long?
根据我们看到的
Well, with the level of damage
整个结肠的损伤情况  是无限期的
we're seeing throughout the colon, indefinitely.
我们很遗憾  霍华德
I'm so sorry, Howard.
我不明白
I don't understand
你为什么要建议做双侧睾丸切除术
why you'd suggest the bilateral orchiectomy
而你甚至都不相信奎因是个女孩
when you don't even believe Quinn's a girl.
我是在回答利姆医生的问题
I was answering Dr. Lim's question.
她说没有别的选择
She said there were no other options,
但是我找到了一个
but I found one.
现在我们在这
And now we're here.
是的
Yes.
你还挺享受干杂活的  是吗
You're actually enjoying this scut work, aren't you?
是的  我们有帮上忙
Yes. We are being helpful.
我们做这个不是在帮忙  莫菲
We're not doing this to be helpful, Murphy.
我们做这个是因为你惹利姆生气了
We're doing this because you pissed off Lim,
而我是附带伤害
and I'm collateral damage.
我们还是有帮上忙
We're still being helpful.
无所谓
Doesn't matter.
无所谓了  比赛结束了
Doesn't matter, competition's over.
是吗
Is it?
我们在这里而不是和病人在一起
We're in here and not with the patient.
没有交流的时间  你还称呼她为「他」
No face time plus you calling her a "He"
也就等同于调查得分很糟糕
equals crappy survey scores.
没关系的  只是场游戏
It's okay. It's a game.
-不重要的  -对我来说很重要
- It's not important. - It is to me.
我是个弃民
I'm a pariah.
这些得分是我们住院医评测的一部分
These scores are part of our resident evaluation.
我们的工作就指望着这些得分了
Our jobs depend on them.
至少我的是
Mine does, at least.
那我们应该把这杂活做得特别好
Then we should do this scut work very well.
菲诺拉打过电话了
Finola called.
她发现咱俩的测试中有一个人的有异常
She found an irregularity with one of the tests
但想再测一次确定一下
but wants to re-run it to be sure.
好  那我们就等她重测
Okay, so we wait until she re-runs it.
马库斯  我们都是医生
Marcus, we're both doctors.
结果不会变的
The results aren't gonna change.
我等了太久了
I waited too long.
都是我的错
It's all my fault.
现在应该是你说
This is the part where you say,
「不  宝贝  不是你的错」的时候了
"No, babe, it isn't."
你有你的目标  其他要优先的东西
You had goals, other priorities.
你说你支持我的职业选择的
You said you supported my career choices,
就像我支持你的一样
just like I supported yours.
我支持你  永远都支持
I do support you. Always.
我很为你骄傲
And I am so proud of you.
但这是我们都知道
But it came at a cost
可能会产生的代价
that we both knew was possible.
-我们应该早点尝试的  -什么时候
- We should have started trying sooner. - When?
当你在三千英里远的达特茅斯教书的时候
When you were 3,000 miles away teaching at Dartmouth?
还是什么  你在争取当上外科主任的时候
Or, what, when you were chasing down head of surgery?
-我们本可以搞定的  -「搞定」
- We would have figured it out. - "Figuring it out"
意味着我和保姆一起养孩子
would have meant me and a nanny raising a baby.
我不想那样
I didn't want that.
我四年前就想说了
I tried to bring it up four years ago,
但你想要提升自己
but you wanted to get your practice up and running.
孩子也不在当时的计划内
A baby didn't fit in that picture, either.
那不一样
It is not the same.
有多少怀孕的女人会被雇佣
How many pregnant women get hired for anything?
又或者当他们发现一个女人家里有个孩子
Or when they find out a woman's got a child at home,
突然间就都是「谁来照顾孩子」
suddenly it's all "Who's gonna take care of the baby?"
没人会问男人这个问题
No one asks men that question.
是啊  现在都不重要了
Yeah, well, none of it matters now.
好吗  因为可能已经太晚了
Right? Because it's probably too late.
我早就知道
And I knew it.
我知道会发生这样的情况
I knew this was gonna happen.
你一直在想这件事
You've been stewing over this.
恨着我  多久了
Resenting me. For how long?
我不恨你  宝贝
I don't resent you, Is.
但是如果你想让我坐下来
But, you know, if you want me to sit here
告诉你那不是你的错
and tell you that it's not your fault,
我  我做不到  对不起
I -- I can't do that, I'm sorry.
你喜欢吗
You like?
门是锁着的
That door was locked.
我知道
Oh, I know.
装有线的家伙那里有个人取消了预定
The cable guy had a cancellation,
所以他给我连接了线路  买一赠一
so he hooked me up, got us a two-for-one.
作为之前的感谢
Little thanks for being so chill earlier.
谢谢  朋友
Gracias, amigo.
你是个什么医生
So, what kind of doctor are you?
外科医生
I'm a surgeon.
A surgeon?
你的这些东西可看不出来你是个外科医生  是吗
Your stuff doesn't say surgeon, does it?
就像赛琳娜和贾斯汀
It's like, uh, Selena and Justin.
不是真的在一起
It doesn't really go together.
家俱像是从很多不同的地方弄来的
Furniture's from, like, a dozen different places.
Fourteen.
卡斯珀的人知道我没钱
The people in Casper knew I didn't have any money,
所以他们给了我些东西来把家修整好
so they gave me things to make a home.
书架是珍妮弗给的
The bookshelf is from Jennifer,
她是市图书馆管理员
the town librarian.
我的桌子和椅子格雷迪先生的餐厅的
My table and chairs are from Mr. Grady's diner.
灯是雪儿的
The lamp is from Sheryl
她在高地教堂的主日学校教书
who teaches Sunday school at Highland Church.
格拉斯曼医生给我的床
Dr. Glassman, he got me my bed.
你不用把整个赠送表都告诉我  但...
Well, you don't have to tell me the whole list, but...
好吧  是的
Okay. Yes.
我拥有的一切都能用
Everything I have works.
没必要换了
There is no need to change it.
厉害
Respect.
我是格拉斯曼医生
I'm Dr. Glassman.
我是医院的院长
I'm the president of the hospital.
一切都还好吗
Is everything okay?
坐
Sit down.
奎因的状况没什么改变
There has been no change in Quinn's condition.
然而  她外婆指控
However, her grandmother has made a claim of child abuse
你和你丈夫虐待儿童
against you and your husband.
她说让奎因服用青春期阻滞剂...
She's claiming that putting Quinn on puberty blockers --
这是她的原话
and these are her words,
「让她觉得做个跨性别者也可以」
"Making her think that being trans is okay" --
是对情感和身体的虐待
is a form of emotional and physical abuse.
说明一下
Now, just to be clear,
我们不认为这些指控
we don't believe any of these allegations
有什么价值
have any merit whatsoever.
我了解我妈  好吗
I know my mom, okay?
她不会放弃的
She's not gonna drop this.
她会去法院
She'll go to court.
她会得到抚养权吗
Could she get custody?
她可以试试  但是利姆医生会作证的
Well, she could try, but, uh, Dr. Lim would testify.
他们会把她放到寄养家庭的
They could put her in a foster home.
泰  她撑不过去的
Ty, she won't make it.
如果我们现在就让奎因做她想做的手术
If we let Quinn do the surgery she wants now,
就都结束了
it'll all be over.
鲁思就没理由告我们了
There will be no reason for Ruth to fight us.
做奎因想要的
Do what Quinn wants.
做那个双侧睾丸切除术
Do the bilateral surgery.
有个问题
There is an issue.
你的检验结果证实了你的精液参数异常
Your tests confirmed abnormalities in the semen parameters.
你说什么
I beg your pardon?
精液分析
The semen analysis.
结果显示你的精子数量和活力都很低
It showed that you have a low sperm count and low motility.
是我的错
It's my fault?
不
No.
我们  我们不用「错」这样的字眼
We -- we do not speak in terms of fault.
百分之十五的夫妇深受不孕烦恼
15% of all couples struggle with infertility,
在那之中  有一半是男方的原因
and of those, 50% have a male factor component.
不是好消息  但也不是没希望了
It's not great news, but it's not a dead end.
那下一步怎么办
So what's the next step?
我会为你们引见阿琼·迪隆医生
I'm gonna refer you to Dr. Arjun Dhillon.
他是杰出的泌尿专家
He's an excellent urologist,
他会给马库斯做个全面的检查
and he'll give Marcus a -- a full physical,
做血检  超声
do some blood work, and an ultrasound.
不可能啊
That can't be right.
-马库斯  -不可能啊
- Marcus. - It can't be right.
马库斯  我们可以解决的
Marcus. We got this.
好吗
Okay?
我们会一起挺过去的
We're gonna get through this together.
为什么不告诉我霍华德的化验结果出来了
Why didn't you tell me Howard's labs came back?
当你把坏消息告诉他的时候我本该在场的
I should have been there when you broke the bad news to him.
这样梅伦德斯就能看到你同情病人的样子
So Melendez could see your touching bedside manner.
不管怎样无所谓了
It doesn't matter anyway.
无所谓  怎么会无所谓
Oh, it doesn't? How the hell not?
那个可怜的家伙要做结肠造口术
The poor guy's getting a colostomy.
我们不可能赢这场比赛的
There's no way we're winning this competition.
你真的一点都不同情
You really have no sympathy
霍华德的遭遇吗
for what Howard's going through?
的确很惨
It's a major bummer, no doubt.
但是我们没时间对每个治疗的病患
But we don't have time to get emotionally invested
都投入那么多感情
in every patient that we treat.
我们的工作就是  进手术室  做手术
Our job is to go in, do the surgery,
然后出来
and get out.
在那之后  他的粪便或是其他什么人的粪便
Afterwards -- his poop, someone else's poop --
都不关我们的事
it's not our problem.
等等
Hey, well, wait.
如果我们给霍华德做一个粪便菌群移植呢
What if we could get Howard a fecal microbiota transplant?
将粪便菌群移植应用于外科病例
FMT for a surgical case?
理论上  我们把健康人的粪便移植给他
Theoretically, we transfer healthy feces to him,
这样可以让重建他机体的微生物群落
it restores good flora to the body,
清除艰难梭菌感染
kills off the CDI,
这样他就不用做任何手术了
and he avoids surgery all together.
这主意听上去可行
We could actually win this thing.
在请示梅伦德斯前我要把相关文献全都查一遍
I'm gonna pull all the research before pitching it to Melendez.
这次的会议名叫
So, this meeting is called
疑难患者会诊
a Challenging Patient Consultation Process.
这名字真烂
The name sucks,
但是这次会议的某些部分我还是挺喜欢的
but there are things about it I do like.
你们要做的就是交流  倾听
All you got to do is talk and listen
并且试着相互理解
and try to understand each other.
有什么好理解的
What's to understand?
鲁思指控我们虐待儿童
Ruth accused us of being child abusers.
有什么可讨论的
And what's to discuss?
我们是奎因的父母
We are Quinn's parents.
我们可以替她做医疗决定
We get to make her medical decisions.
如果奎妮更适合做男生呢
What if Quinnie's better off as a boy?
你根本就不知道奎因经历过什么
You have no idea - what Quinn has been through.
每个孩子都会经历困难
Every kid - goes through rough patches.
每个孩子都会感到迷茫
Every kid is confused.
奎因从三岁起  她就能清楚地告诉我们她是谁
Quinn has always told us exactly who she was, ever since she was 3.
所以你就让奎因玩洋娃娃
So you let Quinn play with dolls.
真了不起啊
Big deal.
你不愿做出改变人生的重大决定
You don't make life-altering decisions
就因为孩子想做小公主
because a child wants to be a princess.
我们让奎因在家随心所欲
We used to let Quinn do whatever she wanted at home.
但是当她在外面的时候
But when she went out in public,
我们让她表现出男孩子的行为举止
we made her present as a boy.
这样对她不公平
It felt false to her.
她不喜欢这样
She hated it.
她讨厌她自己
She hated herself.
她开始变得孤僻  抑郁
She became reclusive, depressed.
一年前  奎因甚至试图自杀
And then a year ago, Quinn tried to kill herself.
抱歉  我来晚了
Sorry I'm late.
如果我们为霍华德进行粪便菌群移植
Howard might not need the colostomy
或许他就不用做结肠造口术了
if we give him - a fecal microbiota transplant.
粪便菌群移植不是已经反复讨论过很多遍了吗
Hasn't the FDA gone back and forth on that?
我们可能会在他的体内引入新的细菌
We could be introducing new bacteria into his system
他可能因此死亡
that could kill him.
出现这种情况的可能性很低
The likelihood of that is low.
但不是没有
But not zero.
可如果我们给他做了结肠造口术
But if we do the colostomy,
这根本不是在帮他
we may not really be helping him.
15%到30%的病患在第一次艰难梭菌感染后
15% to 30% of patients get recurrent CDI
会出现反复艰难梭菌感染
after the initial bout.
这个观点很好
That's a good point.
我想其中有65%的
I believe 65% of that time,
反复艰难梭菌感染会发展为慢性感染
recurrent CDI becomes chronic,
并导致反复住院治疗甚至死亡
which can lead to repeated hospitalizations and death.
我说的数据对吗  克莱尔
Are my numbers right, Claire?
对
Yes.
而最新的研究表明
But recent studies
粪便菌群移植的成功率高达95%
show better than - a 95% success rate with FMTs.
霍华德是一个合适的人选
Howard is a good candidate.
我们应该在他发展为中毒性巨结肠前尽力一试
We should try it before he develops a toxic megacolon.
这不是我们亏欠他和他双胞胎的吗
Don't we owe it to him, to his twins,
至少在做侵入性手术前
to at least try an experimental treatment
尝试一下试验性治疗
before doing an invasive surgery
或许这可以改变他的一生
which will alter his life forever?
你们说得对
You're right.
为他做准备吧
Prep him for the procedure.
我很欣赏你们为病患着想的精神
I appreciate your passionate advocacy for your patient.
你们俩  干得好
Good work, both of you.
现在你倒是会团队合作了
Now you're a team player.
当然  这对我有利
When it benefits me, yes.
说到这  在你做研究的时候
Speaking of which, while you were doing your research,
我在粪便库里找到了和霍华德匹配的粪便
I found Howard a match at the stool bank.
样本几个小时后送到
Sample arrives in a couple of hours.
很好
Great.
等样品送到的时候
I let them know you'd be the designated doctor
我会告诉他们
to handle the medical chain of custody
你是处理医疗监护链的指定医生
when the sample arrives.
所以呢...
So...?
所以你是唯一能处理样品的人
So you're the only person who can handle the sample.
你得自己进行稀释  混合  过滤
You'll have to dilute it, blend it, strain it all on your own.
当然  这是为了防止交叉污染
To safeguard against cross-contamination, of course.
当然
Of course.
你的体温和血压正常
Your temperature and BP are normal.
正常  这意味着什么
Normal. Whatever that means.
典型  平常
Typical. Usual.
符合预期
Expected.
是吗  可是我觉得我跟这些词一点也沾不上边
Yeah, I don't feel like any of those things.
做女生是一种什么感觉
What does it feel like to be a girl?
你生气了
Are you angry?
这是个恼人的问题吗
Was that an inflammatory question?
比起被人们盯着指指点点
I'd rather people ask questions
我宁愿人们问问题
instead of pointing and staring.
以前我看上去是男孩的时候
When I used to look like a boy,
我感到...一切都变了
I felt...different.
学校的孩子们不理解我
The kids at school didn't understand me,
所以他们对我指指点点
so they picked on me.
大部分时间我都自己一个人
I spent a lot of time alone.
当我父母让我做自己的时候
When my parents let me be me,
我感觉...
I felt...
感觉我再也不用去假扮别人
like I didn't - have to pretend anymore.
我感到自由  就像你在一个游泳池里
I felt free, like when you're in a pool
你可以尽情自由地漂浮
and you just let go and float.
我不太会游泳
I'm not a very good swimmer.
我不知道假扮别人
I don't know what it feels like
是什么感觉
to be anyone but me.
我也是
Me, too.
双侧手术比单侧手术风险更大吗
Is the bilateral more risky than the unilateral surgery?
双侧手术最大的问题就是
The big issue with the bilateral
奎因以后再也不能生育了
is Quinn will never be able to have biological children.
如果奎因的父母觉得奎因的思想
If Quinn's parents think that Quinn's mature enough
已经足够成熟坚强
and strong enough in her beliefs,
那手术应该尽快进行
then they should do it now.
这是一个孩子的择期手术
It's an elective surgery on a child.
没有医学上的必要性
There is no medical necessity.
除了  之前的自杀意图
Except with - a previous suicide attempt,
她仍处在危险中
she's still at risk.
现在她的情况已经不同了
Her situation is different now.
在社会角度她已经完成过渡  作为女孩生活了
She's socially transitioned and living as a girl.
但现在仍然没有足够的
But there just isn't enough good data
跨性别儿童及其预后相关数据
on trans kids and their outcomes.
另一方面  我们有很好的理由相信
On the other hand, there's very good reason
保留未来的生育能力是有可能的
to preserve future fertility.
利姆医生和安德鲁斯医生
Dr. Lim and Dr. Andrews
都是非常优秀的外科医生
are both very excellent surgeons,
他们都有自己明确的观点
and they very clearly have some passionate points of view,
但那是他们的观点
but their views are their own.
你们需要决定怎么做对奎因最好
You all need to decide what's best for Quinn.
无论我们如何决定
Whatever we decide,
奎因都将是个女孩
Quinn is still gonna be a girl.
我不知道我能不能接受这一点
I don't know if I'll ever be able to accept that.
我知道我说这话听起来很可怕
I know that makes me sound horrible.
我知道不把家庭放在第一位是什么感觉
I know what it's like to not put your family first,
那让我付出了代价
and it cost me.
付出了十分惨痛的代价
It cost me a great deal.
如果一切重新来过
And if I had to do it all over again,
我会扪心自问
I'd ask myself --
为我爱的人而牺牲性命
is it really worth sacrificing a life
是否胜过为某个荒诞不经的理想而奋斗一生
with someone I love over an idea that may never be?
我们给他们些空间吧
Why don't we give them the room?
叫我来有什么事
I got the page. What's going on.
她刚刚疼得直叫唤  还有呕吐
She started screaming in pain and vomiting.
体温40℃
Temp's 104.
持续进展腹股沟区疼痛  可能是附睾炎
Increased groin pain could be attributed to epididymitis,
肾结石  腹股沟疝...
kidney stones, inguinal hernia...
肿瘤的自重
The extra weight of the tumor
可能引起睾丸发生自身扭转
could be causing the testicle to twist on itself.
睾丸没有血流通过
There'd be no blood flow.
她发生了睾丸扭转
She has a testicular torsion.
需要立即手术
She needs surgery now.
抱歉  你们做好决定了吗
Excuse me. Have you made a decision?
还没有  我是说  有很多东西需要
Not yet. - I mean, there's a lot to --
我们现在就要答案
We need one now.
奎因发生了睾丸扭转
Quinn has testicular torsion.
精索扭曲
The spermatic cord is twisted
切断了血流供应
and cutting off blood supply.
我们需要进行手术
We need to operate.
如果你希望奎因按照她的意愿生活
If you want Quinn to live the way she wants,
那么现在  不要限制她的未来
don't limit her future now.
你听到我妈妈说的了
You heard her when my mom said
她某天可能会想要孩子
she might want kids some day.
她还只是个孩子
She can't even fathom the thought
她不知道自己在想什么
because she's just a child.
就做医学上必须的治疗吧
Just do what's medically necessary.
似乎没有明显的淋巴结肿大
Doesn't appear to be any palpable lymphadenopathy.
很可能是间质瘤
It's likely a stromal tumor,
但还是送病理学检测
but get that to pathology right away.
好的
Yes, sir.
奎因有心动过速和低血压
Quinn has tachycardia and hypotension.
我没看到任何出血
I'm not seeing any bleeding.
心电图正常  不是冠状动脉的问题
EKG's normal. It's not coronary.
二氧化碳和氧含量正常  不是心包积液
CO2 and O2 are normal, so it's not a P.E.
那一定是对麻醉剂的不良反应
It must be a reaction to the anesthesia.
已经推注了液体和血管收缩剂
I'm already pushing fluids and vasoconstrictors.
已经推注了六管注射器  没有泄露迹象
Six syringes in, and no sign of leakage.
好了  我们这里搞定了
Okay, we're wrapped up here.
我们来让霍华德恢复吧
Let's get Howard into recovery.
-干得好  -谢谢
- Well done. - Thanks.
我在考虑把手术过程写出来
I was thinking of writing up the procedure,
也许可以提交出版
possibly submit it for publication.
我很愿意来帮忙
I'd be happy to assist,
看在我之前做过的份上
seeing as I've done it before.
谢谢  但我觉得我可以...
Thanks, but I think I can --
我看过你在《美国外科学》的论文  雷兹尼克医生
I read your paper in AMSURG, Dr. Reznick.
令人印象深刻
You continue to impress.
从你嘴里说出来这话  我真是受宠若惊
Coming from you, I take that as a huge compliment.
你有机会的话  布朗医生
When you get a chance, Dr. Browne,
真应该读一读
you should read it.
我会的
Will do.
我给了升压药
I've given vasopressors
并尽可能地减少了药物
and reduced her meds as much as I can.
她某处在失血
She's losing volume somewhere.
结扎精索时还未有此事
It was dry when we ligated the spermatic cord.
我还没找到出血点
I'm still not seeing the bleed.
可能是断裂神经的迷走神经性刺激
Could be vagal stimulation from the severed nerve.
但她对肾上腺素无反应
But she's not responding to epi.
-败血症吗  -还太早  不会发生感染
- Sepsis? - It's too early for an infection.
她的平均动脉压为20  几乎不够了
Her MAP is 20. She's barely profusing.
好吧  打断一下
Okay, excuse me, guys.
-你把手术服弄坏了  -抱歉
- You're breaking scrub. - I'm so sorry.
体征左腰部青紫斑
Grey-Turner sign.
可能是腹膜后出血
Could be a retroperitoneal hemorrhage.
也许杰瑞德说得对
Jared could be right.
有可能是内出血
It is possible that there's internal bleeding.
睾丸动脉可能会缩回骨盆
The testicular artery can retract up into the pelvis.
虽然很少见  但有这个可能
It's rare, but it can happen.
确实非常罕见  安德鲁斯医生
Rare is an understatement. Dr. Andrews?
我觉得我们别无选择
I don't think we have any other choice.
我们得做剖腹探查  十号刀
We need to do an ex-lap. 10 blade.
莫菲  拉紧
Murphy, retract.
内出血
Internal bleeding.
杰瑞德是对的
Jared was right.
干得漂亮  卡卢医生
Nice call, Dr. Kalu.
谢谢你  先生
Thank you, sir.
卡卢  抽吸
Kalu, suction.
我们需要清晰视野
We need a clear view of the field.
圣何塞圣文德医院
烧退了  你体内的菌群也恢复正常了
Fever's down, and the flora in your system seems to be returning to normal.
-我们期待你的全面恢复  -谢谢你们做的一切
- We expect a full recovery. - Thank you. For everything.
请问我什么时候可以有访客
Do you know when I can have visitors?
我想着你也该问了
I thought you might ask that question.
有几个小朋友很想和你打招呼
There are a couple of eager preschoolers who'd like to say hi.
-爸爸  -凯拉  萨米
- Daddy! - Keira! Sammy!
你们好像长大了
I think you guys have grown!
是这几位医生救了爸爸
These are the doctors that saved Daddy.
雷兹尼克医生和这位...
Dr. Reznick and this is, uh...
抱歉  我忘了你叫什么了
I'm sorry, I forgot your name.
布朗医生
Dr. Browne.
-谢谢  -谢谢
- Thank you. - Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
好了
Okay.
这是谁
Who's this guy?
-熊熊  -熊熊
- Bear Bear. - Bear Bear?
你做了吗
Did you do it?
把两个都移走了吗
Did you remove both?
没有
No.
只移走了癌变的那个
Just the cancerous one.
什么  为什么
What? Why not?
我决定的
That's on me.
凭良心讲  我没法切掉健康的器官
I couldn't, in good conscience, remove a healthy organ.
奎妮
Quinnie.
这是我们的决定
This was our decision.
不  你说了你会站在我这边
No! You said you were on my side!
我们当然站在你这边
Hey, we are. Always.
我们还没来得及好好聊聊
We haven't had enough time to talk,
我们互相之间  以及和你的心理医生
not with each other, with your therapist,
和你的医生
with your doctors.
这么说我要变成男孩了
So I'm gonna turn into a boy.
不会那么快
Well, not right away.
你的内分泌医师
Your endocrinologist will talk to you
会和你聊开始使用女性激素的时间线
about the right timeline for starting feminizing hormones.
你知道...
You know...
想到你以后会有自己的孩子
the thought of having your own kids someday
是个重大决定
is a big decision,
但你长大后就搞不清楚自己到底是否想要孩子
but you never know what you will or will not want once you get older.
人们总是很看重自己生孩子这事
Cis people are always so worked up about having bio kids.
但如果我真的很想要孩子
If I really want a kid that bad,
我可以领养
I can just adopt.
我十八岁时会回来
You know, I'll be back when I'm 18
做我的性别确认手术
for my gender confirmation surgery.
你回来时  我会在这儿帮你
And when you do, I'll be here to help you.
病人的满意度调查来了
Patient satisfaction survey scores are in,
非常接近
and it was very close.
其实算不上  她太友善了
Not really. She's being kind.
恭喜雷兹尼克医生和布朗医生
Congratulations go to Dr. Reznick and Dr. Browne.
-太棒了  -谢谢
- Yes. - Thank you.
恭喜
Congratulations.
谢谢你  肖恩
Thank you, Shaun.
我跟克莱尔合作得很好
Claire and I make a nice team.
你应该很激动
You should be psyched.
是啊  我应该
Yeah. I should be.
战利品属于胜利者
To the victor belong the spoils.
全部付清
Pay up.
你总是做不到谦逊
Humility was never your strong suit.
谢谢  莫蒂默
Thank you, Mortimer.
别都花在一个地方
Don't spend it all in one place.
花掉
Spend it?
我会把它裱起来
I'm gonna frame it.
你怎么想到腹膜后出血的
What made you think of a retroperitoneal hemorrhage?
我做了功课
Homework.
你是对的
You were right.
为共享决策援助做准备很有必要
Prepping for an SDA was important.
我们合作得很好
We make a good team.
奎因不喜欢粉色
Quinn doesn't like pink.
我觉得她会喜欢的
I think she will like these.
希望是的
I hope so.
她更像紫色那种类型
She's more of a purple girl.
你读了摩根发表在《美国外科学》上的论文了吗
Did you read Morgan's AMSURG article yet?
这排在我待办事项的第一条
It is on the top of my to-do list.
我让你去读不是戳你痛处
I didn't tell you to read it to rub it in.
我让你去读是想让你知道你将面临什么
I told you to read it so you knew what you'd be up against.
你觉得我应该更无情一点吗
You think I need to be more cutthroat?
不  那是摩根的秘诀  你不一样
No. That's Morgan's M.O. You're different.
你聪明  你很特别
You're smart, you're special.
站起来反抗  用自己的方式来玩
Rise up, play the game on your own terms.
不要等待
Don't wait for it.
BGM: Rivers And Roads by The Head And The Heart
? A year from now we'll all be gone ?
? All our friends will move away ?
? And they're goin' to better places ?
? But our friends will be gone away ?
? Nothin' is as it has been ?
我听说你救了奎因的命
I heard you saved Quinn's life.
我和杰瑞德一起做到的
Jared and I did.
我喜欢她
I like her.
「她」
"Her."
? And I guess it's just as well ?
你意识到她是个女孩了
So you get that she is a "She."
我有很多疑问
I have lots of questions.
疑问很好
Yeah, well, questions are good.
能导向认识和理解
Leads to awareness and understanding.
以及  谁知道呢  也许还会有认同
And, who knows, maybe even acceptance.
做孩子已经很艰难了
Being a kid is tough enough,
更别提做一个变性的孩子  天啊
But being a trans kid? Oh, man, that's --
简直无法想象
that's off the chart.
我想象不到那会是何感受
I can't imagine how it must feel
外表的不同
to be so different on the outside
甚至比内里更甚
than you are on the inside.
肖恩
Hey, Shaun.
我可以捎你一程
I can give you a lift.
我们可以吃点东西
We could grab a bite.
你说你不能做我的朋友
You said you can't be my friend.
所以  不了  谢谢
So, no, thank you.
? Been talking 'bout ?
? The way things change ?
好的
Okay.
? If you don't know what to make of this ?
兄弟  怎么了
Hey, amigo. What's up?
? Then we will not relate ?
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
? Rivers and roads ?
? Rivers till I reach you ?
? Oh, rivers and roads ?
? Oh, rivers till I reach you ?
? Rivers and roads ?
? Rivers till I reach you ?
你不准备游两圈吗
You're not gonna do any laps or nothing?
不
No.
那你在干什么
Then what are you doing?
试图理解
Understanding.
? Rivers and roads ?
? Rivers till I reach you ?